{"data":[{"question":"I ______ (save) up because I _______ (go) abroad in July.","a":"save\/go","b":"am saving\/am going","c":"saves\/goes","d":"am saving\/go","answer":"2","explain":"- We use the present continuous when you have already decided and arranged to do something","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"5"},{"question":"_______ you _______(need) another blanket or do you feel warm enough?","a":"Are you needing","b":"Do you need","c":"Does you need","d":"Is you needing","answer":"2","explain":"- \"need\" is normally used in the present simple.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"5"},{"question":"- I won't tell you my secret unless you _______ (promise) not to tell anyone.\n- I _______ (promise).","a":"are promising\/am promising","b":"promise\/promise","c":"are promising\/promise","d":"promise\/am promising","answer":"2","explain":"- We use the simple tense in the conditional sentence type I","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"5"},{"question":"Cuckoos _______ (not build) nests. They _______ (use) the nests of other birds.","a":"doesn't build\/use","b":"don't build\/use","c":"don't build\/uses","d":"doesn't build\/uses","answer":"2","explain":"- We use the simple tense to talk about true things in general -> present simple.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"5"},{"question":"The last train _______ (leave) the station at 11.30.","a":"are leaving","b":"is leaving","c":"leaves","d":"leave","answer":"3","explain":"- We use the present simple for things in general or things that happen repeatedly","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"5"},{"question":"- Do you see my car keys anywhere?\n- No, I _______ (look) for them but I _______ (not see) them.","a":"look\/don't see","b":"am looking\/ am not seeing","c":"am looking\/don't see","d":"look\/am not seeing","answer":"3","explain":"- At or around the time of speaking -> present continuous (looking).\n- \"See\" is normally used in the present simple.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"5"},{"question":"- Are you enjoying yourself or would you like to leave now?\n- I _______(enjoy) myself very much. I _______(want) to stay to the end.","a":"am enjoying\/am wanting","b":"enjoy\/want","c":"am enjoying\/want","d":"enjoy\/am wanting","answer":"3","explain":"- at or around the time of speaking -> present continuous (enjoying).\n- \"want\" is normally used in the present simple.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"5"},{"question":"I won't go out now as it _______ (rain) and I _______ (not have) an umbrella.","a":"is raining\/don't have","b":"rains\/don't have","c":"is raining\/am not having","d":"rains\/am not having","answer":"1","explain":"- At or around the time of speaking (now) -> present continuous (raining).\n- Talk about things are true in general -> present simple (don't have).","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"5"},{"question":"- How is Peter getting on at school?\n- Very well. He _______ (seem) to like the life.","a":"is seeming","b":"seems","c":"seem","d":"are seeming","answer":"2","explain":"- \"Seem\" is not normally used in the continuous.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"5"},{"question":"Tom never _______ (do) any work in the garden; he is always working on his car.","a":"does","b":"do","c":"is doing","d":"are doing","answer":"1","explain":"- We use the present simple to say how often you do things (never, always)","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"5"}]}